credit-suisse.com 2019-06-03

# Cookie Policy - Credit Suisse

Latest Update: May 24, 2018

Credit Suisse Group AG and all its affiliates (hereinafter referred to as "Credit Suisse", "we" or "us") are committed to maintaining the privacy of every current, former and prospective customer and website user. We recognize that you entrust important personal information to us, and we wish to assure you that we take seriously our responsibilities in protecting and safeguarding this information. This Privacy & Cookie Policy ("Policy") describes in detail how we deal with information that we collect on this website (the "Site").

This Policy may be updated at any time. Please ensure that you regularly read the latest version of this page. The first paragraph of the Policy tells you when the last update was made.

  * Information we collect
  * Who can access the Information we collect
  * Security of data transfers
  * Protection, Processing and Use of Personal Data
  * How does Credit Suisse treat electronic messages
  * Cookies
  * Links
  * Third Party Cookies and Tracking technologies
  * Social Media Plugins

## Information We Collect

We may collect information about you when you use this Site or when you apply for or use other services offered by Credit Suisse in the following ways:

  * We may also collect personal information about you as a result of us recording certain telephone calls which our employees may have with you, and storing those recordings, in order to satisfy our legal and regulatory obligations or for Credit Suisse Business purposes.
  * If you register to use the password-protected or country-specific portions of our site, we will ask you to provide us with certain information about yourself. This information may include your name, company name, title, address, country of residence, e-mail address, telephone number, account number, assets, income and financial situation. We use such information about you to verify your identity and eligibility to receive certain products or services, to provide information to you about products and services that we believe may be of interest to you, to record your interest in products and services that we offer, and to respond to your requests for information. We may also use cookies or web bugs on such portions of our Site to collect Usage Information, and to facilitate your movement within the Site (e.g. remembering passwords during a session and recording the country you may have elected as your country of residence).
  * We may collect information concerning the attachments you open within newsletters that are sent to you electronically.
  * We may also collect personal information about you from applications, forms or questionnaires you may complete or agreements you enter into with us or in the course of your establishing or maintaining a customer relationship with us, including information about your credit history or financial situation, and your transactions with us or others who provide services to us.

If you decline to provide us with the personal information we require then we may not be able to make investment products available to you or to provide other services to you.

## Who can access the information we collect

Credit Suisse may disclose your information to its affiliates and its and their agents and third party providers inside or outside your country of residence to perform services for Credit Suisse. All parties having access to personal data collected through this website are obliged to respect all applicable data protection laws as well as Credit Suisse internal privacy stipulations.

Credit Suisse may also disclose your information to governmental agencies or entities, regulatory authorities, or other persons in line with any applicable law, regulations, court order or official request, or under any and for the purposes of any guidelines issued by regulatory or other authorities, or similar processes as either required or permitted by applicable law.

## Security of Data Transfers

Please note that data transferred via a public network, such as the internet or an email service, may be viewed by others. Information transmitted via the internet (such as online forms) and content received online may under certain circumstances be transmitted via third-party networks. Credit Suisse cannot guarantee banking secrecy nor the confidentiality of messages or documents transmitted via such open networks or networks from third parties.

If you disclose personal information via an open network or a third party network, you should be aware that your data may be lost or that third parties may be able to gain access to this information and consequently gather and make use of the data without your consent. In particular, while individual data packets are often encrypted, the names of the sender and recipient are not. A third party could therefore be able to draw conclusions about existing bank accounts or business relationships or ones that are subsequently established. Even if both the sender and recipient are located in the same country, data may also be transmitted regularly and without controls via such networks to other countries, including to countries that do not afford the same level of data protection as your country of domicile. We accept no responsibility for the security of your data during transmission via the internet and cannot be held liable for any direct or indirect losses. We ask that you use alternative methods of communication if you deem this to be necessary or appropriate for security reasons.

Data you provide in online forms can be communicated to commissioned third-party companies for order processing and be processed by such companies.

For certain services, we use strong encryption to transfer your data (such as e-banking). In these cases you will be informed separately about the treatment of this data and details concerning encryption. 

## Protection, Processing and Use of Personal Data

We use your personal information to enhance the quality of the products or services we wish to provide to our customers or in connection with your investments with or through us and to maintain contact details for those with whom we deal. We restrict access to personal information about you to those employees, agents or other parties who need to know that information to provide products or services to you or in connection with your investments with or through us. We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to guard your personal information, including firewalls, individual passwords and encryption and authentication technology. We do not use for purposes other than as set out above, or disclose to any third party any personal information about our customers or former customers, except with such customer’s consent or as otherwise permitted or required by law. In cases where we believe that additional products and services may be of interest to you, we may share your personal information with affiliates of Credit Suisse to the extent permitted by applicable law. We may also disclose this information to firms that perform services on our behalf to the extent permitted by applicable law. These service providers are required to treat the information confidentially and use it only for the purpose for which it is provided. Certain jurisdictions may have more stringent privacy requirements that will prevent disclosure of your personal information to any other person or entity, including affiliates.

We will retain your personal information in accordance with applicable data protection laws for so long as it is needed.

Your Personal Data will be processed in accordance with the Credit Suisse Privacy Notice accessible at your domicile through the official Credit Suisse website (e.g. for Switzerland please visit <https://www.credit-suisse.com/ch/en/legal.html>)

## **How does Credit Suisse treat electronic messages**

All electronic messages sent to and from Credit Suisse are automatically retained in a distinct journaling system which preserves the evidential weight of the e-mails. 

They are protected by reasonable technical and organisational measures and may only be accessed in justified cases in line with applicable laws and regulations and internal polices to specific persons in defined functions (e.g. Legal, Compliance, Risk). 

If the visitor uses one of the e-mail addresses or the forms published by Credit Suisse on this website to make contact, he/she expressly authorizes Credit Suisse to respond by the same means either to the sender address or to another indicated address. E-mail is not a suitable means for sending confidential information. Please note that banking secrecy cannot be guaranteed when using any means of electronic communication.

## Cookies

All websites of Credit Suisse Group AG and its affiliates (hereinafter referred to as "Credit Suisse", "we" or "us") use cookies for statistical purposes and to improve user experience and online advertising campaigns. One of the cookies we use is essential for parts of the site to operate and has already been set. This site does not work without cookies. By using this website, you agree to the use of cookies for this purpose.

### What is a cookie?

Cookies are small files which are stored on your device to keep track of your visit to the website and your preferences; as you move between pages, and sometimes to save settings between visits. Cookies help the builders of websites gather statistics about how often people visit certain areas of the website, and help in tailoring websites to be more useful and user-friendly.

For more information on cookies, please feel free to visit the UK Information Commissioner’s Office website ([www.ico.gov.uk](http://www.ico.gov.uk/)) for a more detailed description of the purpose and usage of cookies, and information on how to control and delete cookies from your browser.

### How are cookies used in this website?

The cookies we store on Credit Suisse websites are used to:

  * track the number, and type of visits to the website, and its pages, in order for us to determine which parts of the site are working well, and which need improvement,
  * store your preferences, for screen layouts, including your preferred language and country,
  * gather statistics on the number of users and their usage patterns,
  * improve the speed and performance of the website pages.

### Third party cookies and partners

  * Occasionally we will use third party plug-ins and components to improve the user’s experience and our online advertising campaigns. These components may also use cookies for similar purposes. Neither the third party nor Credit Suisse has access to any data collected by the other via cookies.
  * We may use cookies to display credit Suisse advertisements when you visit third party websites with whom we have marketing relationships.
  * Under certain circumstances, these third parties may collect anonymized information about your use of our and other websites and make these anonymized data available to us, including, but not limited to, your geographical details, your user behavior on a website or the names of websites on which you were shown ads.
  * We may use this information to provide you with more relevant and useful advertising and help us improve the effectiveness of our advertising efforts. 

### Deleting Cookies

You may opt-out of cookies (and the use of this website) at any time, by deleting the cookies that were set by the site. This can be done via the settings of your internet browser, by deleting cache, browsing history and cookies.

## Links

This Site may contain hyperlinks to other websites that are not operated or monitored by Credit Suisse. These other websites are not subject to this Policy and we are not responsible for their content or for the policy they apply to the treatment of personal data. Your use of these links will be at your own risk.
